Mutation it is the key to our evolution.
突变是进化的关键
It has enabled us to evolve from a single-celled organism...
它让我们由单细胞
into the dominant species on the planet.
进化成宇宙生物的主宰
This process is slow, normally taking thousands and thousands ofyears.
过程很缓慢，历经成千上万年
But every few hundred millennia, evolution leaps forward.
但每数十万年间都会出现一突变周期
《X战警》
Niagara Falls. Up...
尼加拉瀑布
the Canadian Rockies, and then it's only a few hundred miles to Anchorage.
加拿大落矶山脉 距离安格拉治不太远
Well, won't it be kind ofcold?
那里很冷吧？
Well, that's the point, stupid.
那才有意思啊
Otherwise, it wouldn't be an adventure.
否则又怎能叫探险？
And when are you gonna do this?
你要何时启程？
I don't know.
不知道
After high school. Before college.
高中毕业后 上大学前
Marie! David? I don't know what happened to him.
玛莉！大卫？ 我不知道他怎么了
- I don't know what  - I just touched him.
- 我不知道怎么了  - 我只是碰到他
I didn't ...I didn't mean
不是故意的
- Call an ambulance! - Don't touch.
- 叫救护车 - 别碰
- Honey  - Just get away from me! - Call an ambulance!
- 甜心 - 不要碰我！ - 叫救护车！
Don't touch me!
别碰我！
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们
we are now seeing the beginnings ofanother stage of human evolution.
人类正面临另一进化阶段
These mutations manifest at puberty...
变种多发生于青春期
and are often triggered by periods of heightened emotional stress.
因情绪起伏而诱发
Thank you, Ms. Grey. It was quite educational.
谢谢，葛雷小姐，颇有教育性
However, it fails to address the issue that is the focus ofthis hearing.
但你偏离了这次会议的主题
Three words: Are mutants dangerous?
也就是：变种人危险吗？
I'm afraid that's an unfair question, Senator Kelly.
你这么问并不恰当
After all, the wrong person behind the wheel ofa car can be dangerous.
有些人开车会出车祸
Well, we do license people to drive.
所以要考驾照
Yes, but not to live. Senator, it is a fact...
但生存没执照 议员，事实上…
that mutants who have come forward and revealed themselves publicly...
变种人一旦暴露身分
have been met with fear, hostility, even violence.
会引起恐慌、敌意、甚至暴力相向
It is because of that ever-present hostility...
为避免变种人受到这种敌意
that I am urging the Senate to vote against mutant registration.
我呼吁取消变种人登记
- To force mutants to expose themselves will only furthet - Expose themselves?
- 暴露变种人身分… - 暴露身分？
What is it the mutant community has to hide I wonder...
为什么要躲藏？
that makes them so afraid to identify themselves?
鬼鬼祟祟的？
I didn't say they were hiding. Let me showyou what is being hidden, Ms. Grey.
他们并没有躲藏 我知道他们躲在哪里
I have here a list of names of identified mutants...
这是一份美国境内
living right here in the United States.
变种人名单
- Senator Kelly  - Now, here's a girl in Illinois who can walk through walls.
- 凯利议员  - 有一个女孩能穿墙而过
Now, what's to stop her from walking into a bank vault...
假如她潜入银行保险库？
or into the White House or into their houses?
或白宫 或各位的家中
- Senator Kelly  - And there are even rumors, Ms. Grey,
- 凯利议员 - 我还曾听说…
of mutants so powerful that they can enter our minds and control our thoughts,
变种人能感应并控制人类思想
taking our God-given free will.
剥夺我们自由的意愿
I think the American people deserve the right to decide...
我们有权决定
whether they want their children to be in school with mutants,
孩子是否要 变种人做老师或同学
to be taught by mutants.
或远离他们
Ladies and gentlemen,
各位先生女士
the truth is that mutants are very real,
事实上，变种人的确存在
and they are among us.
而且就在我们身边
We must know who they are, That's right!
我们得知道他们是谁
And, above all, we must know...
彻底的研究他们
what they can do.
知道他们的能力
Eric.
艾瑞克
- What are you doing here? - Why do you ask questions...
- 你来这里干什么？ - 为何要问些
to which you already know the answers?
早知道答案的问题？
Don't give up on them, Eric.
别放弃人类
What would you have me do, Charles? I've heard these arguments before.
要我怎么办？别再浪费唇舌了
It was a long time ago.
那是过去
Mankind has evolved since then.
人类进化了
Yes
对
into us.
进化成变种人
You sneaking around in here, Charles?
你用心电感应闯进这里
Whatever are you looking for?
想要找什么？
I'm looking for hope.
我在找寻希望
I will bring you hope, old friend.
我会给你希望
And I ask only one thing in return.
我只有一个要求
Don't get in my way.
别阻扰我
We are the future, Charles, not them.
未来属于变种人
They no longer matter.
人类被淘汰了
This is it.
到了
Where are we?
这是哪里？
I thought you said you were gonna take me as far as Laughlin City.
你说要载我去洛芬市
This is Laughlin City.
这里就是
Gentlemen, in all myyears,
各位
I've never seen anything like that.
我从没见过这种事
Are you gonna let this man walk away with your money?
你们甘心让他赢走钱？
I'll fight him!
我上场！
Ladies and gentlemen, our savior!
各位观众，救星上场
Whateveryou do, don't hit him in the balls.
别打他的要害
You said anything goes. Anything goes, but he'll take it personal.
你不是说没限制的 是没有限制，但他会发火
Ladies and gentlemen
各位
tonight's winner and still king ofthe cage
今晚的冠军仍是拳王…
the Wolverine!
金刚狼
You want something new, honey?
要试试新饮料吗？
Or are you sticking with water?
还是只要喝水？
I'll have a beer.
来罐啤酒
Ellis Island, once the arrival point for thousands ofAmerican immigrants...
艾利斯岛曾是美国移民的入口
is opening its doors again.
今日又再度成为焦点
Preparations are nearly completed for the upcoming United Nations world summit.
这里将举行联合国高峰会
With nearly every invitation confirmed,
世界各国元首都将出席
the event promises to be the largest single gathering ofworld leaders in history.
参与国之多，史无前例
The leaders of over 200 nations will discuss issues ranging from the world's economic climate...
两百多国元首将讨论经济
and weapons treaties to the mutant phenomenon and its impact on our world stage.
军备协议 以及变种人对世界造成的影响
Many American legislators have contended...
美国议员认为首要议题…
that debate over mutant issues should be the primary focus of what is, on the surface
是取得管理变种人的共识
You owe me some money. Come on, Stu. Let's not do this.
把钱还我 算了，我们走吧
No man takes a beating like that without a mark to show for it.
人不可能被揍而身上没受伤的
Come on, buddy. This isn't gonna be worth it.
算了，别跟他争了
I know what you are. You lost your money. Keep this up, you'll lose something else.
我知道你是什么东西 再缠下去，你输的将不只是钱
Come on, buddy.
算了
Look out!
当心！
Get out of my bar, freak.
滚出去，怪物
- What the hell are you doing? - I'm sorry. I needed a ride.
- 你在干什么？ - 抱歉，只想搭个便车
- Thought you might help me. - Get out.
- 我以为你会帮我 - 走开
Where am I supposed to go? I don't know.
要我去哪里？ 不知道
You don't know oryou don't care? Pick one.
你是不知道还是不在乎？ 随便你怎么想
I saved your life. No, you didn't.
我救过你 才没有
You don't have anything to eat, do you?
有东西可以吃吗？
I'm Rogue.
我叫小淘气
Were you in the army?
你当过兵？
Doesn't that mean you were in the army?
那牌不是证明你当过兵吗？
- Wow. - What?
- 哇 - 怎么了？
- Suddenly my life doesn't look that bad. - If you'd prefer the road...
- 我的生活还不算苦 - 你想下车…
No. No. It looks great.
不，不是 这车很棒
Looks cozy.
很舒适
Put your hands on the heater.
手放暖炉上
I'm not gonna hurt you, kid.
我不会伤害你
It's nothing personal. It's just that...
你别误会，只是…
when people touch my skin, something happens.
人家每次碰我的皮肤便会发生…
What? I don't know.
怎样？ 不清楚
They just get hurt.
就是会受伤
Fair enough.
好吧
When they come out, does it hurt?
你的爪子伸出时，会觉得痛吗？
Every time.
每次都会痛
So, what kind ofa name is Rogue?
怎么会叫小淘气？
I don't know. What kind ofa name is Wolverine?
不知道，那你怎么会叫金刚狼呢？
My name's Logan.
我叫罗根
Marie.
我叫玛莉
You know, you should wear your seat belt.
你该系好安全带
Look, kid. I don't need advice on auto safety from...
不用你提醒…
You all right?
你还好吗？
- Kid, are you all right? - I'm stuck!
- 你没事吧？ - 我被卡住了
Weren't you supposed to bring someone back with you?
你没把人抓回来？
- What happened? - They knew.
- 怎么回事？ - 有救兵
Charles.
查尔斯
- Where is the mutant now? - With them.
- 变种人呢？ - 被救走了
I have made the first move.
我先发制人
That is all they know.
他们就只能知道这么多
Come. The U.N. Summit is approaching.
走，高峰会即将举行
Time for our little test.
去测试一下
Where's he going?
他去哪里了？
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Over here.
到这里来
Where are you going?  This way.
你要去哪里？来！
He's over there.
他在那里
Let's go.  What's your hurry?
走吧！ 好饿喔
Good morning, Logan.
罗根，早安
I'd like your definitions of weak and strong anthropic principles...
你们记得星期三要交人类定理的
on my desk on Wednesday.
优缺点报告
That'll be all.
下课了
Bye, Professor. Bye, Kitty.
教授，再见 再见
Physics.
物理课
I'm Charles Xavier. Would you like some breakfast?
我是X教授，想要吃早餐吗？
- Where am I? - Westchester, New York.
- 我在哪里？ - 纽约，西彻斯特
You were attacked. My people brought you here for medical attention.
你遭到攻击 他们带你来疗伤
- I don't need medical attention. - Yes, ofcourse.
- 我不需要疗伤 - 看得出来
- Where's the girl? - Rogue? She's here. She's fine.
- 那女孩呢？ - 小淘气吗？她在这里，她很好
Really.
真的
Ah, Logan, I'd like you to meet Ororo Monroe, also called Storm.
罗根，她叫梦露，绰号暴风女
This is Scott Summers, also called Cyclops. Hello.
他叫史考特，绰号独眼龙
They saved your life.
他们救了你
I believe you've already met Dr. Jean Grey.
你应该见过琴葛雷
You're in my school for the gifted. For mutants.
这里是变种人学校
- You'll be safe here from Magneto. - What's a Magneto?
- 万磁王是不会追来的 - 万磁王？
A very powerful mutant who believes that a war is brewing...
他的超能力惊人
between mutants and the rest of humanity.
他想挑起变种人与人类的战争
I've been following his activities for some time.
我一直密切观察他
The man who attacked you is an associate of his called Sabretooth.
今天攻击你的叫大钢牙
Sabretooth?
大钢牙
Storm.
暴风女
What do they call you? Wheels?
你的绰号是…轮椅人？
This is the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
这个实在太荒谬了
Cyclops, right? You wanna get out of my way?
独眼龙，对吗？ 别挡我的路
Logan, It's been almost 15 years, hasn't it?
罗根，已经15年了
Living from day to day, moving from place to place,
日复一日，南来北往
with no memory ofwho or what you are.
想不起自己是谁
Shut up.
住口
Give me a chance.
给我个机会
I may be able to help you find some answers.
我或许能帮你找到答案
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
You're not the only one with gifts.
不只你有超能力
Where are you going?  Where's he going?
你要去哪里？ 他要去哪里？
What are you doing there?
你来做什么？
What is this place?
这是什么地方？
Anonymity is a mutant's first chance...
变种人隐姓埋名
against the world's hostility.
躲避敌意
Hey, no powers!
喂，不能作弊啊！
To the public, we're merely a school for gifted youngsters.
这是启发超能力的学校
Cyclops, Storm andJean were some of my first students.
独眼龙、暴风女 是我首届的学生
I protected them, taught them to control their powers...
我保护他们，并且教他们如何控制能力
and in time, teach others to do the same.
他们同时也教导学童
The students are mostly runaways.
这些逃家的孩子
Frightened, alone.
恐惧又寂寞
Some with gifts so extreme that they've become a danger...
失控的超能力
to themselves and those around them.
可能伤害到别人
Like your friend, Rogue.
例如小淘气
Incapable of physical human contact, probably for the rest of her life,
不能有肌肤接触 可能一辈子都如此
and yet here she is with others her own age,
如今她找到了同伴
learning being accepted, not feared.
一起学习，不受排斥、不恐惧
- John. - Sorry.
- 约翰 - 抱歉
I'm Bobby. What's your name?
我叫巴比 你呢？
- Rogue. - What'll happen to her?
- 小淘气 - 她以后会怎样呢？
Well, that's up to her. Rejoin the world as an educated young woman...
将由她自己决定 重新投入社会或…
or stay on to teach others...
留在学校教书
to become what the children have affectionately called X-Men.
也就是孩子口中的：X战警
Welcome to Mutant High.
欢迎你加入
But the school is merely a public face.
虽然外观是学校
The lower levels, however, are an entirely different matter.
里面其实大有文章
When I was a boy, I discovered I had the power to control people's minds,
小时候我发觉我能心电感应
make them think or do whatever I wanted.
能够操纵他人言行
When I was 17, I met a young man named Eric Lensherr.
我17岁时认识了艾瑞克
He, too, had an unusual power.
他也具有超能力
He could create magnetic fields and control metal.
能产生磁场控制金属
Believing that humanity would never accept us,
他因为人类的仇视
he grew angry and vengeful.
而充满恨意
He became Magneto.
他就是万磁王
There are mutants out there with incredible powers, Logan,
变种人的能力惊人
and many who do not share my respect for mankind.
而且很多并不喜欢人类
If no one is equipped to oppose them, humanity's days could be over.
如果缺乏反制能力 人类将可能灭亡
I'll make a deal with you, Logan.
跟你谈个条件
Give me 48 hours to find out what Magneto wants with you,
给我48小时查出万磁王为何找你
and I give you my word that I will use all my power...
我会尽全力帮助你
to help you piece together what you've lost...
恢复记忆
and what you're looking for.
找出你的人生意义
Senator, listen, you favor gun registration, yes?
议员，你赞成枪枝登记？
Well, some of these so-called children...
变种小孩的威力
possess more than 10 times the destructive force ofany handgun.
胜过枪枝
No, I don't see a difference. All I see are weapons in our schools.
没有差别，我只知道校园充满危机
Well, that's fair enough. All right.
好吧，这主意不错
So?
怎么样？
It's gonna be close. A vote this loaded is always close.
变数很大 结果很难预料
What about the U.N. Summit? The whole world will be watching.
高峰会怎么办？全球瞩目
Maybe there's some way you could use that to your advantage.
你或许能从中获利
We're Americans, Henry.
这里是美国
Let the rest of the damn world deal with mutants in their own way.
我们排斥变种人
You know this situation?
目前的情况
These mutants?
这些变种人…
People like this Jean Grey?
例如琴葛雷
If it were up to me, I'd lock 'em all away.
我主张将他们全关起来
It's a war. It's the reason people like me exist.
这是场战争 因此世界需要我
Where the hell are we?
我们在哪儿？
Pilot!
驾驶员！
People like you are the reason I was afraid to go to school as a child.
因为你这种人害我小时候不敢上学
- I'm sorry. - Forwhat?
- 对不起 - 为什么？
If I hurt you.
我伤了你
So, couldn't wait to get my shirt off again, huh?
又迫不及待脱我衣服
The metal is an alloy called adamantium.
超硬度合金
Supposedly indestructible. It's been surgically grafted to his entire skeleton.
无坚不摧 以手术移植入骨骼
How could he have survived a procedure like that?
动这种手术怎么能存活？
His mutation. He has uncharted regenerative capability,
他的超能力 他拥有超强回复能力
which enables him to heal rapidly.
伤口能迅速痊愈
This also makes his age impossible to determine.
所以很难判断他的年纪
He could very well be older than you, Professor.
他可能比教授年纪大
Who did this to him? He doesn't know.
谁做的？ 他不知道
Nor does he remember anything about his life before it happened.
也不记得动手术前的事
Experimentation on mutants.
拿变种人做实验
It's not unheard of.
不是没听过
But I've never seen anything like this before.
但我没有见过有这种手法
What do you think Magneto wants with him?
万磁王有何意图？
I'm not entirely sure it's him Magneto wants.
我还不确定万磁王想用他做什么
Toad has a wicked tongue, Senator.
癞蛤蟆有邪恶的舌头
Just like you.
就跟你一样
Who are you people? Where's Henry?
你们是谁？亨利呢？
Mr. Guyrich has been dead for some time, Senator.
亨利死了很久了，议员
But I've had Mystique here keep you company.
是魔形女陪着你
She takes so many shapes.
她能够任意变身
Whatever you do to me, you'll make me right.
如果你伤害我…没有好处
Every word I've spoken will be confirmed.
反而证明我说的没错
Are you a God-fearing man, Senator?
你畏惧上帝吗？
That's such a strange phrase.
这句话真奇怪
I've always thought of God as a teacher,
我认为上帝是导师
as a bringer of light, wisdom and understanding.
是明灯、智慧与抚慰
You see, I think what you really are afraid of is me.
其实你心中畏惧的是…我
Me and my kind. The Brotherhood of Mutants.
我们变种人，拥有超能力者
Though it's not so surprising, really.
我并不觉得意外
Mankind has always feared what it doesn't understand.
人类一向惧怕陌生事物
Well, don't fear God, Senator,
不要畏惧上帝
and certainly, don't fear me.
也不要怕我
Not anymore.
你将再也不需要害怕了
What do you intend to do to me?
你想要干什么？
Let's just say God works too slowly.
应该算是替天行道
I think you'll be comfortable here.
希望你住得舒适
- Where is your room? - With Scott down the hall.
- 你住哪里？ - 我跟史考特住在楼下
Is that your gift? Putting up with that guy?
你的超能力是…忍受他？
Actually, I'm telekinetic. I can move things with my mind.
我可以用念力隔空移物
Really? What kinds ofthings?
是吗？移动什么？
All kinds ofthings.
任何物体
I also have some telepathic ability.
我还能心电感应
- What, like your Professor? - Nowhere near that powerful.
- 像X教授一样？ - 没那么强
But he's teaching me to develop it.
我还在学习
I'm sure he is.
我相信
So read my mind. I'd rather not.
来感应一下我的思想 不要
Come on. You afraid you might like it?
来嘛，怕爱上我？
I doubt it.
不可能
What do you see?
看到什么？
Scott.
史考特
Good night, Logan.
罗根，晚安
You gonna tell me to stay away from your girl?
要我离你女友远一点？
If I had to do that, she wouldn't be my girl.
她绝不可能看上你
Hmm. Well, then, I guess you've got nothing to worry about,
那你没什么可担心的吧
do you, Cyclops?
对不，独眼龙
Yeah, it must just burn you up that a boy like me saved your life, huh?
我救了你，令你很不爽？
You ought to be careful. I might not be there next time.
小心，下次没那么幸运
Oh, and, Logan,
罗根
stay away from my girl.
离我女友远一点
Logan.
罗根
Logan. Logan, wake up.
罗根，你醒醒
Help me.
救命啊
Somebody help!
快来人啊！
Scott, grab a pillow.
史考特，拿枕头
It was an accident.
那是意外
-  Logan? - What happened?
- 罗根 - 怎么回事？
- Is she all right? - She'll be all right.
- 她还好吗？ - 她没事的
What did she do to me?
她把我怎么了？
Whenever Rogue touches someone, she takes their energy, their life force.
小淘气吸收接触者的能量
In the case of mutants, she absorbs their gifts for a short while.
也就是变种人的超能力
In your case, your ability to heal.
所以她的伤口迅速痊愈
I feel like she almost killed me.
我觉得差点死掉
If she'd held out any longer, she could have.
再久一点确实会送命
How are we feeling, Senator? Advanced, I hope.
你还好吗？希望你进化了？
What the hell have you done to me?
你把我怎么了？
Senator, this is pointless. Where would you go?
议员，别挣扎了，你要去哪？
Who would take you in now that you're one of us?
如今谁还会接受你？ 你现在和我们一样了
Tommy, let it go! Tommy, please let it go!
汤米，放了它 拜托放了它
I'm telling Mommy.
我要告诉妈妈
Is that a mutant?
他是变种人吗？
...of this week's U.N. Summit.
…高峰会的首要议题
With the leaders of over 200 nations attending,
两百多国元首到达艾利斯岛
the Secret Service has transformed Ellis Island...
戒备森严
into a veritable Fort Knox for tomorrow night's opening gala.
盛会于明晚举行
Ellis Island rests less than one mile from the shores of Manhattan.
艾利斯岛距离曼哈顿不足一英里…
Rogue.
小淘气
Bobby. Rogue, what did you do?
巴比 小淘气，你做了什么？
They say that you're stealing other mutants' powers.
听说你窃取超能力
No, no. I borrowed his powers.
不，我只是借用
You never use your power against another mutant.
不该用超能力对付变种人
I had no choice.
我不得已
No, you have to understand me. If I were you,
你要明白 如果我是你
I'd get myself out of here.
我会离开这里的
What do you mean? Listen, the students are freaked.
什么意思？ 听着，学生都被吓坏了
Professor Xavier's furious. I don't know what he'll do with you.
X教授很生气，你要当心
I think it'll be easier on your own.
你最好离开这里
You should go.
你快走吧
What are you looking for, Eric?
艾瑞克在找什么？
It's strange. There are more powerful mutants out there.
奇怪，外面那么多变种人
Why should this one be so important to him?
为什么万磁王会选上他？
Maybe it's his way with people. You don't like him.
因为他的待人方式？ 你不喜欢他？
- How could you tell? - Well, I am psychic, you know.
- 你怎么知道？ - 我能心电感应
- Where is she? - Who?
- 她在哪里？ - 谁？
Rogue.
小淘气
She's gone.
她走了
Welcome, Professor.
X教授，请进
Welcome to Cerebro.
这里是搜寻室
This certainly is a big, round room.
好大的圆形建筑
The brain waves of mutants are different from average human beings.
变种人的脑波不同于人类
This device amplifies my power,
增强脑波装备能加强我的能力
allowing me to locate mutants across great distances.
用于搜寻变种人
That's how I intend to find Rogue.
我打算利用这个找到小淘气
Why don't you just use it to find Magneto? I've been trying.
何不找出万磁王？ 我试过
But he seems to have found some way to shield himself from it.
但他有办法避开
How would he know how to do that?
他怎样做到的？
Because he helped me build it.
他帮我建造这个系统的
Now, ifyou'll excuse me.
各位，失陪一下
Have you evet
你曾操作…
Used Cerebro?
搜寻室？
No. It takes a degree ofcontrol,
没有 必须很有控制力
and, uh, for someone like me, it's
对我而言…
Dangerous.
很危险
now boarding on track four.
请登上4号月台
She's at the train station.  Where is it?
她在火车站 哪个车站？
A few miles west of here. Logan, you can't leave the mansion.
西方几英里外 罗根，你不能出去
- It'sjust the opportunity Magneto needs. - I'm the reason she took off.
- 别中了万磁王的计 - 她因我而离开
- We had a deal. - She's all right. She's just upset.
- 我们有协定 - 别担心，她只是闹脾气
Storm, Cyclops, find her. See if you can talk to her.
暴风女、独眼龙去找她回来
What? Where's my motorcycle?
怎么了？ 我的摩托车呢？
Hey, kid.
小淘气
I'm sorry about last night.
昨晚很抱歉
Me too.
我也是
- You running again? - I heard the professor was mad at me.
- 你又要流浪？ - 听说X教授很生气
- Well, who told you that? - A boy at school.
- 谁说的？ - 一个男同学
When's the last time you saw her? She was supposed to meet me for lunch.
她去哪了？约好共进午餐
You look around. I'll check with the ticket agent.
你四处找找，我去问问售票员
Welcome, Professor.
X教授，请进
- You think I should go back. - No, I think you should follow your instincts.
- 你要我回去吗？ - 由你自己决定
The first boy I ever kissed...
我初吻的男孩
ended up in a coma for three weeks.
昏迷了3周
I can still feel him inside my head.
景象历历在目
And it's the same with you.
如今又发生在你身上
There's not many people that'll understand what you're going through,
很少人能体会你的心情
but I think this guy's Xavier's one of them.
但X教授不一样
He seems to genuinely wanna help you,
他真心想帮助你
and that's a rare thing...
这是很难得的
for people like us.
他关心像我们这样的人
So, what do you say?
你说呢？
Give these geeks one more shot?
再给他们一次机会？
Come on. I'll take care of you.
我会照顾你的
- You promise? - Yeah.
- 你保证？ - 对
Yeah, I promise.
对，我保证
Come along now.
走，叫你别跟这种人说话
She's about 17. Uh, my height.
她约十七岁，跟我差不多高
Has brown hair, and she-
棕色头发，她…
Scream for me.
死期到了
Quit playing around.
别偷懒
You must be Wolverine.
你一定是金刚狼
That remarkable metal doesn't run through your entire body, does it?
你全身骨骼都是超合金？
Stop! Stop it!
不！住手！
What the hell do you want with me?
你为何找上我？
You? My dear boy, whoever said I wanted you?
你？拜托，谁说我要找你？
Young people.
年轻人
All right, hold it. Hold it right there.
不准动！通通不准动
Stay where you are. Put your hands overyour heads now.
把手举起来，双手放在头上
You Homo sapiens and your guns.
没有用的人类和武器
- That's enough, Eric. - Let them go.
- 艾瑞克，够了 - 放了他们
Why not come out where I can see you, Charles?
查尔斯，有本事站出来
What do you Want her for?
为何要抓她？
Can't you read my mind?
你读不到我的心思吗？
What now? Save the girl?
你想救她
You'll have to kill me, Charles. And what will that accomplish?
得先杀了我 又有何意义？
Let them pass that law. They'll have you in chains with a number burned into your forehead.
他们通过法例，让人类在你的额头上编号
It won't be that way.
不会那样的
Then kill me and find out.
那就杀了我再去验证
Huh? Then release me.
否则放了我
Fine.
好
Care to press your luck, Charles?
想试试运气吗？
I don't think I can stop them all.
子弹不可能全挡住
Still unwilling to make sacrifices.
心肠还是太软
That's what makes you weak.
这就是你的弱点
Good-bye, Charles.
查尔斯，再见
You said he wanted me.
他不是要抓我
I made a terrible mistake.
我错了
His helmet was somehow designed to block my telepathy.
他的头盔挡住了感应
I couldn't see what he was after till it was too late.
我没能及时阻止他
Where are you going? I'm gonna find her.
你要去哪里？ 去找她
How? The traditional way. Look.
怎么找？ 用眼睛找
Logan, you can't do this alone.
罗根，别单独行动
Who's gonna help me? You? So faryou've all done a bang-upjob.
谁能帮我？你们只会捅篓子
Then help us. Fight with us.
帮助我们，与我们并肩作战
Fight with you? What, join the team? Be an X-Man?
并肩作战？成为X战警？
Who the hell do you think you are? You're a mutant.
拜托，别忘了你们是变种人
The whole world out there is full of people that hate and fear you.
人类既惧怕又恨你们
And you're wasting your time trying to protect 'em? I got better things to do.
还要保护人类？ 我还没那么无聊
You know, Magneto's right. There's a war coming.
万磁王说的对，战争将临
- You sure you're on the right side? - At least I've chosen a side.
- 你选对了阵营？ - 至少我做了抉择
I'm looking for Dr. Jean Grey.
我找琴葛雷博士
Senator Kelly.
凯利议员
I'm Professor Charles Xavier.
我是X教授
I was afraid if I went to a hospital, they would...
我担心到医院，他们会…
Treat you like a mutant?
把你当作变种人？
We're not what you think. Not all of us.
我们不是敌人，有善有恶
Tell it to the ones who did this to me.
去向加害于我的人说这话吧
Senator...
议员
I want you to try and relax.
试着放轻松
I'm not going to hurt you.
我不会伤害你
Welcome to the future,
未来属于变种人
brother.
兄弟
The machine emits radiation that triggers mutation in ordinary human beings.
这机器发出辐射引发人体突变
But the mutation is unnatural.
这种突变是非自然的
Kelly's body is rejecting it. His cells began...
外来基因遭到身体排斥
to break down almost immediately.
细胞几乎全坏死了
- What effect does radiation have on mutants? - There appears to be none.
- 辐射会影响变种人吗？ - 不会
But I fear it will seriously harm any normal person exposed to it.
但会伤害普通人类
- So what does Magneto want with Rogue? - I don't know.
- 他为何抓小淘气呢？ - 不知道
Wait a second.
等一下
You said this machine draws its power from Magneto...
你说机器吸取万磁王的能力
and that it weakened him.  Yes
今他元气大伤 对
In fact, it nearly killed him.
事实上，他几乎丧命
He's gonna transfer his power to Rogue...
他想借助小淘气的力量
and use her to power the machine.
来操作机器
Is somebody there?
有人在吗？
Yes. I'm here.
有 我在这里
Please don't leave me.
请别离开我
Don't want to be alone.
我不想一个人独处
All right.
好
Do you hate normal people?
你恨普通人类吗？
Sometimes.
有时候会
Why?
为什么？
I suppose...
因为…
I'm afraid ofthem.
我怕他们
I think you've got one less person to...
你害怕的人
to be afraid of.
将又少一个
Cyclops, you and Storm ready thejet. I'm gonna find Rogue.
你们准备喷射机，去找小淘气
Jean, get Logan a uniform. Whoa, wait a minute.
琴，给罗根制服 慢着
He's not coming with us, is he? Yes
让他一起去吗？ 对
I'm sorry, Professor, but he'll endanger the mission. And if-
教授，他会破坏任务的
Hey, I wasn't the one who gave the train station a new sunroof, pal.
火车站的天窗是谁开的？
No, you were the one who stabbed Rogue through the chest. Scott.
谁的利爪刺伤小淘气？
Hey, why don't you take your little mission and stick it up your...
谁稀罕加入你们
Senator Kelly is dead.
凯利议员死了
I'm going to find her.
快去找小淘气
Settle this.
解决问题
I'm sorry.
抱歉
You can still hear me, can't you?
你听得到我说话吗？
You've taught me everything in my life that was ever worth knowing.
你传授我宝贵的知识
And ifanything happens,
你不要担心…
well, I'll take care of them.
交给我来处理
Jean?
琴
Jean!
No!
不要！
Jean?
琴?
Jean.
琴
Answer me. Please.
回答我，拜托
I know where Magneto's going.
我知道万磁王去哪里
Magnificent, isn't she?
自由女神真壮观
- I've seen it. - I first saw her in 1949.
- 我看过了  - 1949年首次见到她
America was gonna be the land oftolerance,
美国敞开大门
of peace.
迎接和平
Are you going to kill me?
你要杀了我吗？
- Yes. - Why?
- 是的 - 为什么？
Because there is no land oftolerance. There is no peace.
因为没有宽容、没有和平
Not here or anywhere else.
世界各地都一样
Women and children, whole families destroyed...
当权者任意残害
simply because they were born different from those in power.
弱势的族群
Well, after tonight, the world's powerful will be just like us.
今晚，当权者将成为变种人
They will return home as brothers.
加入弱势的族群
As mutants.
变种人
Our cause will be theirs.
让他们亲身体验
Your sacrifice will mean our survival.
牺牲你造福变种人
I'll understand if that comes as small consolation.
了解之后你会比较安心
Put her in the machine.
带她上机器
I'll raise it.
开始了
Magneto is here. Liberty Island.
万磁王在这里，自由岛
Now, presumably, his objective is to mutate the world leaders at the U.N. Summit...
假设他的目标是岛上的
on Ellis Island.
高峰会元首
He doesn't know his machine kills.
他不知道辐射会致命
And judging from what the Professor saw, if Magneto gave Rogue enough powet-
据X教授所说 若小淘气吸收万磁王的能力
He could wipe out everyone in New York City.
纽约市民都会死
We can insert here at the George Washington Bridge,
我们穿越华盛顿桥
come around the bank just off of Manhattan.
低飞到曼哈顿岛
We land on the far side of Liberty Island here.
降落在自由岛上，这里
What about harbor patrol? Radar?
巡逻队和雷达怎么办？
If they have anything that can pick up ourjet, they deserve to catch us.
若我们那么逊，被逮活该
You actually go outside in these things?
真要穿上这个？
Well, what would you prefer, yellow spandex?
还是你想穿黄色紧身衣？
Okay, there's the bridge. I'm taking her down.
桥在那边，我们低空掠过
Storm, some cover, please.
暴风女，请掩护一下
Toad, Mystique, stay sharp. We're not alone.
你们提高警觉，有人来了
And you stay here.
你待在这里
Once I give my power to the girl, I'll be temporarily weakened.
我给那女孩超能力后会变得虚弱
You'll be my only defense.
你要负责保护我
Sounds like a storm's coming.
好像有暴风雨
- Sorry. - You call that a landing?
- 抱歉 - 技术还真烂
The torch.
在火炬上
The first dignitaries started to arrive about an hour ago,
一小时前首批国家元首到达
greeted with a sort of garden-party atmosphere,
布置得如花园般的
which was designed to entertain them,
宴会场地
as the others traversed the rigid security.
其实警戒森严
There's someone here. Where?
这里有人 在哪里？
I don't know. Keep your eye open. Logan.
不知道，提高警觉 罗根
Damn it.
可恶
Anything? I know there's someone here. I just can't see 'em.
找到了吗？ 我感觉得到，看不到
Wait! Wait!
慢着！
All right, back up. Back up.
退后，退后
Jean!
琴
Oh, God.
天啊！
Don't move.
别动
Don't you people ever die?
你们怎么死不了啊？
Do you know what happens to a toad when it's struck by lightning?
癞蛤蟆被闪电击中会怎样？
Same thing that happens to everything else.
会死得很惨
Logan, is that you?
罗根，是你吗？
The other one ain't far away.
复制人在附近
Come on. We have to regroup.
走，跟其他人会合
I know, but there's a problem.
好，但问题是…
You're not part of the group.
你不是自己人
Hey, hey, it's me.
是我
- Prove it. - You're a dick.
- 证明 - 你是蠢蛋
Okay.
好吧
Everybody get out of here.
大家快离开
What is it? I can't move.
怎么了？ 我动不了
Ah, my brothers.
变种兄弟们
Welcome. And, you,
欢迎
just point those claws of yours in a safer direction.
至于你…爪子最好安分点
You'd better close your eyes.
你最好闭上眼睛
Storm, fry him.  Oh, yes.
暴风女，用闪电 好呀
A bolt of lightning into a huge copper conductor.
铜片最易传电
I thought you lived at a school.
真没知识
For those of you who may not be familiar with the historical significance
具历史意义的自由女神…
Mystique?
魔形女
Mystique? I've seen Senator Kelly.
魔形女 我见过凯利议员
So the good senator survived his fall...
他没有摔死？
and the swim to shore.
还游到岸上
He's become even more powerful than I could have imagined.
他比我想像中强
- He's dead. - It's true.
- 他死了 - 真的
I saw him die. Like those people down there will die.
我看着他断气 那些人也都会死
Are you sure you saw what you saw?
你确定没看错？
I would also like to thank the president ofthe United States...
本人在此感谢美国总统
for hosting this event...
在纽约市主持
under the lights of the great city of New York.
这一场盛会
Why do none ofyou understand what I'm trying to do?
为何你们不明白我的用意？
Those people down there, they control our fate and the fate ofevery other mutant.
他们掌控了所有变种人的命运
Well,
看…
soon our fate will be theirs.
让他们去亲身体验
Help! Please help me!
救命！谁救救我
You're so full ofshit.
一派胡言
If you were really so righteous, it'd be you in that thing.
若真有本事，你去亲自操作机器
Help! Somebody help me!
救命！救救我啊！
Please!
拜托
Somebody please help me!
谁来救救我
Somebody!
来人啊！
Help
救我
Logan!
罗根
- I'm sorry, my dear. - Don't do this.
- 我很抱歉，亲爱的 - 不要这样
This is mine.
这是我的
You owe me a scream.
你死定了
Hey, bub. I'm not finished with you yet.
小子，我们没打完
Jean.
琴
Scott, when I tell you, open your eyes. No.
听我指示张开眼睛 不
- Trust me. - You drop something?
- 相信我 - 这是你的？
Now.
现在
Thanks. Don't mention it.
谢了 不客气
We gotta get her out of there. Cyclops, can you hit it?
快救小淘气，用雷射光
-  The rings are too fast. I'll kill her. - Just shoot it.
- 转速太快 - 快发射
- Storm, can you get me up there? - I can't control it like that.
- 暴风女，你送我上去？ - 我无法精准控制高度
- You could fly right over the torch. - Then let me go.
- 你或许会掉入海里 - 让我去
If I don't make it, then at least you can still blast the damn thing.
我如果失败，你用雷射光炸了它
All right, do it.
好吧
Jean, use your power. Try to steady him.
琴，用念力控制高度
Hang on to something.
站稳了
Scott, wait.
史考特，等一下！
I have to. Just wait.
不能等了！ 等一下！
I have a shot.
我锁定目标了
I'm taking it.
要发射了
Come on.
醒醒
Hey, this one's alive. Let's get him out of here.
这人还活着，快送医
Welcome back.
终于醒了
I knew you'd find your way.
我知道你会醒的
I had you to guide me.
你引领着我
How did we do?
情况如何？
Oh! Oh, that tickles.
好痒
Hey.
喂！
How're you feeling? Fantastic.
你还好吗？ 好极了
That was a brave thing you did.
你非常勇敢
Did it work? Yeah. She's fine.
成功了吗？ 对，她没事了
She took on a few of your more charming personality traits for a while.
只是她几乎成了你的翻版
But we lived through it.
反正习惯了
I think she's a little taken with you.
我想她爱上你了
Well, you can tell her my heart belongs to someone else.
告诉她我有心上人了
- You know, you and I - How's the professor?
- 你知道，你跟我… - X教授好吗？
He's good. Good.
很好 那就好
There's an abandoned military compound at Alkali Lake in the Canadian Rockies,
加拿大落矶山脉有个废弃军营
close to where we found you.
我们在附近找到你
There's not much left, but you might find some answers.
线索虽然不多，但或许你会找到答案
- Thankyou. - Are you going to say good-bye to them?
- 谢谢 - 你要跟他们道别？
The Mutant Registration Act lost its main proponent today...
提倡变种人登记制度的凯利议员
with the dramatic reversal of Senator Robert Kelly,
戏剧性的转变立场
who until this time had provided the loudest voice in the cry for mutant registration.
他是变种人登记制的提案人
I was wrong on this particular issue.
我承认错了
And I hope in time I may be forgiven. Thankyou.
希望大家原谅
The Mutant Registration Act continues to draw support...  Mystique.
变种人登记法案仍在酝酿… 魔形女
Son of a bitch.
可恶
From many Parents Rights groups who feel threatened...
家长恐惧校内
by unidentified mutants in their school systems.
隐藏的变种学童
In a related story,
另外
the body of Senator Kelly's longtime aide, Henry Guyrich, was found today.
凯利议员的助理亨利的尸体被发现
Preliminary coroner reports seem to indicate that Guyrich was mauled by a bear.
法医验尸后认为是遭到熊攻击
You running again? No, not really.
又要去流浪了吗？ 不是
I have some things to take care of up north.
我去北方处理一些事
I kind of like it.
挺漂亮的
I don't want you to go.
我不要你走
I'll be back for this.
我会回来拿的
Doesn't it ever wake you in the middle ofthe night?
你会半夜惊醒吗？
The feeling that someday they will pass that foolish law...
担心某日他们会通过法律
or onejust like it and come for you...
不公平的残害你…
and your children?
和你的子孙
It does, indeed.
确实
What do you do when you wake up to that?
惊醒时，你该怎么办呢？
I feel a great swell of pity for the poor soul...
我可怜那些无知的人，那些…
who comes to that school looking for trouble.
挑衅的人
Why do you come here, Charles?
你为何来此？
Why do you ask questions to which you already know the answers?
你为何总问早知道答案的问题？
Oh, yes.
对了
Your continuing search for hope.
你还在寻找希望
You know this plastic prison oftheirs won't hold me forever.
这种塑胶监狱是关不住我的
The war is still coming, Charles, and I intend to fight it...
战争还没结束，我要反击
by any means necessary.
不惜一切代价
And I will always be there
我会尽一切力量阻止你的
Old friend.
老朋友